I'm here at Fort Nashborough, and you might be wondering what I'm holding.
Well, it's a VR headset.
I'm with Nashville Adventures, and we're going to do a VR city tour.
So let's go check it out and talk to Paul, the owner.
You are the founder of Nashville Adventures,
and I'm understanding it's some sort of VR kind of city tour.
Give me the whole rundown about what you guys do.
You got it. So I started this about three years ago when I started
this as a passion project, started this with thirty six hundred dollars.
And we have grown exponentially since then to the point
that our history tours, our coffee crawls, our club crawls, our ghost tours are beginning
to kind of dominate this market.
And I wanted to have something that people could enjoy even if they really weren't giant
history buffs.
So, you know, I kind of want this to be if you're 12 years old and you don't like your
history teacher, you're still going to have a blast with us learning history.
And so we felt the best way to do that was with XR tours.
And so everyone kind of knows XR tours, you know, virtual reality, you put these goggles
on and it takes you to someplace.
This is a different type of thing.
It's the beauty of Nashville.
Everyone thinks it's Broadway, and that's a block that way.
But the birth of the city is right next to it.
This is the heartbeat of the city.
It's this Fort Nashborough right here.
And this XR Tour will take you there.
I'm really pumped about it, as you can tell.
Yeah, I'm going to get to try this out in real time,
which I'm pretty thrilled.
This is not your typical city walk-through tour.
So we're going to give it a go.
You're going to put me through.
I'm going to get the headset on.
So let's go try it out.
Rock and roll.
Let's do it.
Oh, I see them walking towards me.
And I can see my hand right here.
You see how it's placed in front of you?
It doesn't replace the environment and adds to it.
Now, you got to do me a small favor.
Now you got to turn around.
I'm hearing noises of animals right now.
Oh my god.
Oh, there's chickens.
Isn't that crazy?
And there's people standing out here.
So the great thing about this is that, obviously,
there's none of that here.
You are, in the most realistic way possible,
seeing what Fort Nashborough was all the way in the 1790s.
night. And believe it or not, you can go to the chickens and feed the chickens, feed the horses,
and all this stuff here. The experience is just one of many. So you have Fort Nashborough,
where you're sitting here, you get to see John Donelson come up, give you the spiel
about what makes Fort Nashborough important, see that environment. You're going to be able to
go to Printers Alley, which had all these famous artists there at one time. You're going to see
the state capitol and have that built in front of you. And at the end of this, as a crescendo,
you're going to be able to stand right there and have a cannon experience and either do one of two
things. You can help destroy the old Tennessee Titans stadium or you can have you can blow up
a pirate ship with the Alabama flag on it. Very cool. We want to embrace both the humor
that is you know the reality of what we live in. We want to have fun but at the same time
expose you to a history that most people have no idea that's right next to the action of
master. No it's so cool. You're seriously transported. There's a chicken over here.
I know you can't see it, but I can it's walking towards me, but this is so neat
It's nothing like I've ever done before. It's so immersive. There's people over here and horses
I probably look crazy, but you know what I'm talking about. Yeah, yeah, but I'm loving it. It's so interactive
It's such a different take on that like plastic city tour
I tell you what I love about this is even if you're reluctant to do a history tour
You're going to enjoy this. Yes, this is very very cool
I agree. And I'd say the passion we have, we get great tours no matter what. This added variable
in the equation helps ensure a universal understanding of something I love more than
anything else. Yeah. This city is beautiful from day one to now.